{"tossups": [{"question": "Blackbeard died on this state\u2019s island of Ocracoke. Virginia Dare\u2019s birth on an island in this state made her the first person of English descent born in the Americas. A carving of the word \u201cCroatoan\u201d was found on an island in this state\u2019s Outer Banks that was home to a \u201cLost Colony.\u201d Roanoke was found in, for ten points, what state whose capital was named after Sir Walter Raleigh?", "answer": "<b> North Carolina</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "One of these conflicts effectively ended with the capture of the Taku Forts. A letter that said, \u201cLet us ask, where is your conscience?\u201d was sent to the victorious monarch of these wars. One of these wars began when officials boarded and searched the<em> Arrow</em>. In the first of the Unequal Treaties, Hong Kong was ceded to the winner of these wars as part of the Treaty of Nanking. For ten points, name these 19th century wars in China over a British poppy export.", "answer": "<b> Opium</b> War(s)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "One of these events that mainly affected Monterey and Santa Cruz Counties in 1989 temporarily cut off coverage of the World Series and began near Loma Prieta Peak. The Mission District burned in a fire that occurred after one of these events that destroyed the original flag used in the Bear Flag Revolt; that event was centered near the Golden Gate. For ten points, name these type of natural disaster that largely destroyed San Francisco in 1906.", "answer": "<b> earthquake</b>s", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "A villa in Florence inspired the name of a map of this island known as the Castello Plan. Seyseys, the leader of the Canarsee, led a negotiation for this island. An artillery section built along the southern portion of this island was known as the Battery. Members of the Lenape tribe were supposedly given 60 guilders by Peter Minuit to transfer ownership of this island to the Dutch. For ten points, name this island of New York City that is home to Wall Street.", "answer": "<b> Manhattan</b> <b>Second Quarter</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "In this election year, Governor Scott Walker survived a recall election and Tammy Baldwin was elected as the first openly LGBT Senator in US history. A remark that \u201cthere are 47 percent of Americans who will vote for the President no matter what\u201d hurt the Republican Presidential challenger in this election year, who ran on a ticket with Paul Ryan. For ten points, name this year in which Mitt Romney ran against Barack Obama, who won a second term as President.", "answer": "<b> 2012</b> (prompt on \u201c12\u201d)", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {}, {"question": "This event\u2019s leader stumbled upon Pompey\u2019s Pillar, where his etched signature remains to this day. Fort Mandan was constructed by participants of this event, who included a slave named York. After setting out from St. Louis, this event\u2019s leaders were joined by Toussaint Charbonneau and his Shoshone wife, Sacagawea. For ten points, name this early 19th century expedition that Thomas Jefferson deployed to scout the Louisiana territory.", "answer": "<b> Lewis and Clark</b> Expedition (accept<b> Corps of Discovery</b>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "Alberto Granado and this man were given a raft to sail on the Amazon River after treating lepers. This man supported Jacobo Arbenz, but when his wife Hilda Gadea was arrested, he moved to Mexico. This man journeyed for nine months on a motorcycle across South America. This revolutionary fought in a revolution that deposed Fulgencio Batista after sailing on the<em> Granma</em>. For ten points, name this Argentine Marxist revolutionary who helped Fidel Castro in Cuba.", "answer": "Ernesto \u201cChe\u201d<b> Guevara</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "This philosopher identified the lowest-level, indivisible units of substance as \u201cmonads.\u201d This thinker formulated a principle of \u201cpre-established harmony\u201d in his Discourse on Metaphysics, and he codified the\u201cprinciple of sufficient reason\u201d in a 1710 work whose title coined the term \u201ctheodicy.\u201d The inspiration for Pangloss in Voltaire\u2019s<em> Candide</em> was, for ten points, what German thinker who concluded that ours is the best of all possible worlds?", "answer": "Gottfried Wilhelm von<b> Leibniz</b>", "metadata": "Philosophy - Philosophy"}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "<b>In this war, French forces captured enemy plans during the Mechelen Incident. During</b> <b>this conflict, the French navy was destroyed at the Battle of Mers el-Kebir to (+)</b> <b>prevent</b> <b>it from falling into enemy hands. The initial French plan for this conflict involved rushing to the River Dyle to fight with Belgium. After an attack through the Ardennes circumvented the (*)</b> Maginot Line in this conflict, French troops were encircled at Dunkirk. For ten points, name this war in which France was conquered by Nazi Germany.", "answer": "<b> World War II</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b>This figure hired a group of men all named Elmer so that when he called for them, they would all show up. This man was said to have drilled holes in maple trees with two huge</b> <b>mosquitoes he had caught. This man owned a cow named (+)</b> <b>Lucy, as well as an animal</b> <b>that he found freezing in the snow that turned a certain color when exposed to his fireplace. This owner of (*) </b> Babe the Blue Ox was said to have created the Grand Canyon while dragging his axe behind him. For ten points, name this giant lumberjack of American folklore.", "answer": "Paul<b> Bunyan</b>", "metadata": "Mythology - Mythology"}, {"question": "<b>This empire made its conquered lands part of the Twelve Doors. In an epic from this</b> <b>empire, a leader wounded an enemy with an arrow with the spur of a (+)</b> <b>rooster. The</b> <b>Kouroukan Fouga constitution and the Gbara assembly were central to this empire, whose founder defeated Sumanguru at the Battle of Kirina. (*) </b> Sundiata Keita founded this empire, which controlled trans-Sahara trade. For ten points, name this empire that devalued gold after its ruler Mansa Musa went on a hajj in 1324.", "answer": "<b> Mali</b> Empire", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "<b>A man born in this city posed a problem about the growth rate of a rabbit population in his book</b><em><b> Liber Abaci</b></em><b>. A value approximating the Golden Ratio can be found by dividing</b> <b>two successive terms in a sequence named for that man born in this city, (+)</b> <b>Fibonacci.</b> <b>Vincenzo Vivani claims that</b><em><b> De Motu</b></em><b>\u2019s central idea, that objects of different masses have the same (*) </b> acceleration, was verified by a man\u2019s experiment in this city. For ten points, name this Italian city, where balls were allegedly dropped by Galileo from its namesake leaning tower.", "answer": "<b> Pisa</b>", "metadata": "Science - Other Science - Math"}, {}, {"question": "<b>African-American soldier William Williams was one of four men killed during an attack on this fort carried out by Alexander Cochrane. This fort held an object created by Mary</b> <b>Pickersgill that inspired a poem later (+)</b> <b>set to the tune \u201cTo Anacreon in Heaven;\u201d that</b> <b>poem was written by a lawyer visiting (*)</b> Baltimore who observed an attack on this fort in 1814. For ten points, name this fort whose defense inspired Francis Scott Key to write the words of \u201cThe Star-Spangled Banner.\u201d", "answer": "Fort<b> McHenry</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b>The death of a leader in this location led power to shift to the Flensburg government under Karl Donitz. Hans Krebs shot himself in the head as troops closed in on this location,</b> <b>located under the (+)</b> <b>Chancellery building. This location was the last of its function,</b> <b>Chancellery building. This location was the last of its function,</b> <b>preceding the Eagle\u2019s Nest and (*)</b> <b>preceding the Eagle\u2019s Nest and (*)</b> Wolf\u2019s Lair. The most famous occupant of this location took cyanide before having his body burnt. For ten points, name this underground command post where Adolf Hitler committed suicide.", "answer": "<b> Fuhrerbunker</b> (accept descriptive answers relating to Adolf<b> Hitler</b>\u2019s<b> bunker</b> in Berlin; prompt on partial answers, like \u201cHitler\u2019s hiding spot\u201d and \u201cthe Berlin bunker\u201d)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b>A ruler with this first name supposedly forged a letter from his mother Emma in order to lure and capture his step-brother Alfred; that ruler had the nickname \u201cHarefoot\u201d and was the son of Canute the Great. A later ruler with this first name used an army of (+) huscarls to defeat his brother Tostig at the Battle of Stamford Bridge, but was killed by an (*)</b> arrow to his eye less than a month later. For ten points, give this name shared by the Anglo-Saxon king who lost to William the Conqueror at the Battle of Hastings.", "answer": "<b> Harold</b> (accept<b> Harold</b> I or<b> Harold</b> Harefoot; accept<b> Harold</b> Godwinson after \u201chuscarls\u201d is read) <b>Extra Question</b> Only read if you need a backup or tiebreaker! (1) <b>While leading striking workers in this state during the Battle of the Overpass,</b> <b>Walter Reuther was beaten by security forces at the River Rouge Complex. The</b> <b>Willow Run (+) plant in this state produced a B-24 Liberator every 63 minutes during</b> <b>World War II. Anti-Semitic conspiracies were published by this state\u2019s (*)</b> <em>Dearborn</em> <em>Independent</em> newspaper, whose owner revolutionized the assembly line during his production of the Model T. For ten points name this home state of the Ford Motor Company. ANSWER:<b> Michigan</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}], "bonuses": []}